Now is where we get to probably the more
complicated part. Hopefully, you're all
pretty comfortable writing a for loop
that just goes over numbers. Let's go
back over to our slideshow. So, I'm
going to rewind. So, now what I want you
to do is I want you to look at where
each box is that we've opened in
comparison to the arrow. So, we're
looking at the first box. That's where
our arrow is.
Well, we opened the box directly next to
it.
and then the one next to it and then the
one next to it and then the one Oh, and
then we swap them and then we open up
the one next to it and then we open up
the one next to it. So, just looking at
what the box does,
you'll notice that the gap just slowly
moved all the way to the end.
Interesting. Well, then let's see. Then
we shifted the arrow and then we opened
boxes.
and we slowly shifted that box gap to
the end. So, we slowly shifted the box
over. But where did the box start when
we moved this arrow? Well, we moved the
arrow and it started at one plus the
arrow. So, wherever the arrow was, it
started one over and then we went
through the end of the array and then we
moved our arrow and then we compared one
over from the arrow and moved to the end
of the array. Hopefully you can see that
the box that we're comparing to always
started at one over from the arrow, but
then it continued in a straight line all
the way through the end of the array.
And if that is sounding very much like
the arrow's original movement where it
started at the beginning of the array
and moved to the end of the array, good
cuz we're going to use another for loop.